# AHMAD ZULQARNAIN QADRI

**Position: NETWORK SYSTEM SUPPORT ENGINEER** 

**Experience: 6+ YEARS** 

Mobile: 00971-50-411 8014 Visit Visa: SHORT TERM

**Location: DUBAI** 

Email: azgarnain@hotmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/ahmad-zulgarnain-gadri

[MCP|MCSA|MCTS|MCITP|MCT|ITIL|VSP|VTSP|VCP|CCNAR&S|HCNAR&S|HCNA Sec. |MCS|CS|MS-CS]

# **KEY SKILLS**

Hyper-V ITIL Symantec SEP 14 Virtual Desktop Infrastructure Solar-winds Kaspersky antivirus SCCM VMware vSphere **IT-Support Terminal Servers** IBM/HPE/Huawei/ DELL EMC Storage **Project Manager** Microsoft SCVMM **SQL Server** Research Analysis **Communication Skills** Windows Server Routing and Switching

Linux 5.0 6.0 7.0 Exchange Online & 2016 Office 365
Linux-LVM Windows 2012 2016 & 2019 Azure

### **CAREER SUMMARY**

Having the vast experiences in the field of designing and implementing IT infrastructure solutions and Systems Administrations and Sr. Solutions Architecture having 6+ years of vast industrial experiences at Principles Side and End Users locations/ at the well-known leading organizations and IT firms related to Desktops support, Storage and Servers Data Center virtualization and network infrastructure implementations and upgradations of services on premises and converting in to cloud and datacenter virtualization infrastructures on classified market's products like VMware, Microsoft, Cisco, Huawei IBM HPE DELL EMC. Performed and managed RPO and RTO of the datacenter applications services and databases backups by the state of art products line such as Veeam and Symantec Backup Exec. solutions for resultant set of policies and protections, I am an enthusiastic individual and good team player with achievements of state of arts training and skills, completed presales task of designing BoQs /RFPs and Costing Analyzing's many of solutions with HLD and Visio illustrations related to DELL EMC Servers Storages CI/ HCI Datacenters, Microsoft VMware VSAN and most valued start of art. Well known IT Solutions,

# **PROFESSIONAL WORK EXPERIENCES**

DESIGNATION: ENTERPRISE SOLUTION ARCHITECT ORGANIZATION: ASTRONTECH DISTRIBUTIONS

(Partnered by the well-known Leading Principles Dell EMC, Sangfor, VMware, Microsoft and Kaspersky/Symantec)

**Tenure:** May 2018 to October 2019(Project Based)

- Executed and designed projects of Switching and routing devices Cisco and Huawei, Hands on implementation on VMware server appliance on new infrastructure on VMware 6.7 Appliance and VMware High Availability and VMware Migration, Designed and plan industrial's scale migrations to O365 and Microsoft Azure AD Connect and ADFS
- Experienced of Designing BoQ/RFP and Costing Analyzing dexterity and Designed Visio Diagram of Solution related to DELL EMC Server Storage CI/ HCI Datacenters

DESIGNATION: PRESALES SPECIALIST (ESG)

ORGANIZATION: COMPUTER MARKETING PVT-LTD

(Partnered by the well-known Leading Companies like HP & Huawei Partner)

Tenure: Feb 2017 to May 2018

- o Measured for prospecting, qualifying and generating new sales leads recommend potential products or services to management by collecting customer information and analyzing customer needs.
- Proceeded Storage systems knowledge of the following architectures (DAS, SAN, NAS, Hierarchical storage systems, RAID,
   Fiber Channel), Backup/Restore technologies and iSCSI environments

DESIGNATION: PRESALES CONSULTANT/ BUSINESS DEVELOPMENT MANAGER (ESG)

ORGANIZATION: MEGA PLUS PAKISTAN PVT LTD.

(Partnered by the well-known leading Principles like Dell, CISCO Microsoft & HUAWEI)

**Tenure:** July 2014 to January 2017

- Elaborate BoM/RFI of Huawei, DELL EMC Server Storage CI/ HCI Datacenters solutions according to End User needs with the liaising with Principle according to the Leads.
- Responsible for prospecting, qualifying and generating new sales leads recommend potential products or services to management by collecting customer information and analyzing customer needs.



**DESIGNATION:** MANAGER ENTERPRISE TECHNOLOGY SERVICES

ORGANIZATION: KARACHI ELECTRIC SUPPLY CORP.

(The one of the largest leading Power & Energy organizations and any of countrywide Energy power companies)

**Tenure:** December 2012 to June 2014

- o Managed/Administrated Exchange 2010, Blackberry Enterprise Server and Cloud Computing Working on special projects, leading teams, managing routine technical/operational activities. Understanding departmental mission and vision.
- Contributed by supporting activities that are subject to business measurements, impact customer satisfaction, or impact immediate costs or Hands on experience with hypervisor and compute virtualization technologies (VMware, vSphere, VCenter, Microsoft Hyper-V and SCVMM 2012.

#### **PROJECTS & ACCOMPLISHMENTS**

- o Installed and configured web applications to help in recruiting company for score the candidates and assisted being a system administrator in Recruitment firm.
- Installed and accomplished Lync 2013/Exchange Mailbox and CAS Servers at K Electric for 5000+ Nodes
- Installed and migrated Exchange 2003 Server to Exchange 2010 at K Electric on installed SCVMM 2012 and Configured with test run different of Cloud Services Servers, Upgraded Windows Server 2008 to Windows Server 2012, performed mirroring on installed SQL 2008/2012 servers' Databases at K Electric. Installed and Configured SharePoint 2010 and performed SharePoint 2007 Servers to 2010 migration on production servers at K Electric.
- Designed most of proposal and projects on different on premises and cloud messaging and Cloud virtualizations Platforms such as Office 365 E3 and Azure and VMware Virtualization projects as well as up and running the switching and firewall solutions being a Solution Architect from the many of IT vendors and platforms to the Banking, Manufacturing, Aviation and Educational Sectors.
- Orchestrated and managed delivery of Windows Sever Infrastructure services and to provide administration support efficiently, effectively, consistently with optimal resource
- o Administered the designed, implemented, support & maintenance of Centralized Active Directory and ADS based applications, Collaboration, Privilege Access Management, Symantec EV, Hyper V, Virtualization, SAN storages
- Deployed and administered MS and applications Patching, policy-based filtering of email rules, AV scanning, not allowing email server as blacklisted in global spam DBs
- Evaluated & recommended IT hardware / software based on business needs, manage Hyper V Manager, Cluster console & System Center Patch Installation local assistance when routine assistance needed Production support of operating systems Security compliance responsibilities Familiar with latest data retention and storage policies and industry standards Backup and Restore Architecture Configure backup schedules.

#### **ACADEMIC EDUCATION**

DEGREE/CERTIFICATIONUNIVERSITYYEARMASTER OF SCIENCE IN COMPUTER SCIENCEMOHAMMAD ALI JINNAH, KARACHI2018

# **CERTIFICATIONS ACCREDITATIONS & TRAININGS**

→MCT-Microsoft Certified Trainer

→ MCSA -Microsoft Certified Solutions Associate

→MCTS -Windows Server 2008 Active Directory (70-640)

→MCTS-Microsoft Network Infrastructure (70-642).

→ MCTS-Microsoft Application Infrastructure (70-643) → MCTS-Microsoft Windows 7 Applications (70-680)

→ MCITP-Microsoft Server Enterprise Administrator (70-647)

→MCP-Microsoft Certified Professional

→ITIL-Information Technology Infrastructure Library.

→SAP-Systems, Applications and Products-BASIS

- →VTSP-VMware Technical Sales Professional
- → VSP-VMware Sales Professional
- →MCSA Windows Server 2012
- →VMware Certified Datacenter Virtualization Professional 6.7
- →HCNA R&S
- →HCNA Sec
- →CCNA 200-125
- →VMSP-Veeam Sales Technical Professional
- →VMSTP-Veeam certified Technical Professional

# PERSONAL INFORMATION

Father's Name: Mushtag Ahmad

Marital Status: Married